# JIAWEI LIU

### RESEARCH INTEREST

My research aims at making infrastructure software fast, reliable and easy-to-use. I focus on computer systems and its programming and reliablity support. Specifically, I am interested in using software analysis techniques to make machine learning systems reliably fast.

# **EDUCATION**

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, IL, US

Ph.D. in Computer Science; GPA: 4.0/4.0

Tongji University, Shanghai, China

B.Eng. in Computer Science

Aug. 2021 - Present Advisor: Lingming Zhang

Sept. 2017 - Jul. 2021

### **PUBLICATION**

Pre-print | Finding Deep-Learning Compilation Bugs with NNSmith

Jiawei Liu, Jinkun Lin, Fabian Ruffy, Cheng Tan, Jinyang Li, Aurojit Panda, Lingming Zhang. [paper]

OOPSLA'22 | Coverage-Guided Tensor Compiler Fuzzing with Joint IR-Pass Mutation

Jiawei Liu, Yuxiang Wei, Sen Yang, Yinlin Deng, Lingming Zhang. [code] [artifact] [paper]

ACMMM'21 OSC | Fast and Flexible Human Pose Estimation with HyperPose

Yixiao Guo, Jiawei Liu, Guo Li, Luo Mai, Hao Dong. [code] [paper]

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Intern at OctoML Advised by: Dr. Yuchen Jin, Dr. Sunghyun Park, Prof. Tianqi Chen Topic: Dataflow Pattern Language

Research Assistant at PL/FM/SE Group, UIUC

Advised by: *Prof.* Lingming Zhang

Intern at DAMO Academy, Alibaba-Inc Advised by: Dr. Yuanwei Fang, Prof. Yuan Xie

Research Assistant at NYU Systems Group

Advised by: Prof. Jinyang Li

Research Assistant at Hyperplane Lab, Peking University

Advised by: Prof. Hao Dong, Prof. Luo Mai

Intern at AI Lab, ByteDance Ltd.

Advised by: Guanzhe Huang, Dr. Chuanxiong Guo

May. 2022 - Aug. 2022

Apr. 2021 - Present

Topic: Fuzzing

Mar. 2021 - Aug. 2021 Topic: GNN Serving

Jul. 2020 - Mar. 2021

Topic: Video Analytics Jan. 2020 - Aug. 2020

 ${\bf Topic:}\ Pose\ Estimation\ Systems$ 

Feb. 2020 - Jul. 2020 Topic: DNN Serving

## NOTABLE ACHIEVEMENTS

Oct.2020 Dec.2019
Dec 2019
D cc. 2010
Nov.2019
Aug.2019
Nov.2018

## **OPEN-SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS**

I embrace and grow with open-source communities.

I lead the HyperPose (1200+ stars) project to support performance-critical computer vision applications. I also actively contribute to TVM. For example, I implemented the dataflow pattern language of Relax IR.

Existing machine learning systems leverage optimization techniques to exploit every bit of performance – my research facilitates the correctness of those non-trivial optimizations, helping detect and fix over 110 real-world bugs for existing deep learning frameworks (over 70 fixed). Notably, my work Tzer has detected 49 bugs in TVM. In addition, my newer work NNSMITH, a general graph-level fuzzer, has detected 65 bugs for TVM, TensorRT, ONNXRuntime and PyTorch.

## **TALKS**

Coverage-Guided Tensor Compiler Fuzzing with Joint IR-Pass Mutation

• SAMPL Lunch Talks, University of Washington

May 2022

• UIUC Software Engineering Seminar, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

April 2022

# STUDENT MENTORING

Sen Yang (Summer 2021)

Yuxiang Wei (Summer 2021)

Undergraduate at Tongji Univ.  $\rightarrow$  UIUC Ph.D.

Graduate at Fudan Univ.  $\rightarrow$  Yale Ph.D.

# SKILL STACK

Familiar with code optimization, parallel programming, automated testing, visualization and machine learning.

Common: C++ (primary), Python, Go, Rust, Docker, Shell, Git, SQL, LATEX, Grafana, GDB

High-Perf. Computing: LLVM, CUDA, C++ Thread Library, gRPC, Kafka, Protobuf, Thrift, OpenMP

Machine Learning & Systems: PyTorch, TensorRT, TensorFlow, TVM, ONNX, OpenCV

System Correctness: Z3, Dafny, LLVM Sanitizers, Valgrind